Register of the Rudolph Altrocchi Papers, 1900-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
Rudolph Altrocchi Papers,
1900-1945
55001
Altrocchi, Rudolph, 1882-1953
3 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes (1.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, office diary, reports, speeches, military orders, newspaper clippings, postcards, posters, sheet music, and printed matter, relating to American war propaganda work in Italy and Lyons, France.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; Propaganda, American.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Propaganda.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.
Biographical Note
1882, October 31 born, Florence, Italy
1908 A.B., Harvard
1914 Ph.d., Harvard
1918, June-Sept. director of oral propaganda in Italy. American Bureau of Public Information, Rome
1918-1919 2d lt., Infantry, Liaison Service, A.E.F., Lyons, France
1915-1927 assistant professor and associate professor of Italian, University of Chicago
1928-1947 professor of Italian, University of California
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, office diary, reports, speeches, military orders, newspaper clippings, postcards, sheet music, and printed matter, relating to American war propaganda work in Italy and Lyons, France.
Container List
- Office diary of Liaison Service, A.E.F., Lyons, France, May 1918-April 1919 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1915-1945
- Correspondence, undated
- Letters from Henry L. Stimson, 1912 and 1929
- Letters of introduction
- Form letters
- Liberty Loan Drive (Box 2)
- Maps
- Membership and award certificates
- Mementos
- Military Training Camp, Plattsburg, N.Y. (1916)
- Newspaper clippings
- Orders, travel certificates, and passports
- Pamphlets and printed matter
- Poetry (Box 3)
- Postcards
- Programs, announcements and posters
- Receipts for expense accounts
- Reports, speeches, notes, letters to editors
- Sheet music
- Speakers campaign
- War ration book
- Photographs
  - 16 photos of the staff of the American bureau of Public Information, Rome, Italy, 1918 and of military burials at Lyons, France, 1918-1919. 7 photos of other scenes including air flights at Campo de Marte in 1910, Queen Margherita of Italy in 1898 or 1899, and postcards (Folder A)
  - 1 photo of troops of the A.E.F. in military parade in France, 1919 (Folder mB)